

ALEXIS BENTER

WWW.ALEXISBENTER.COM ALEXISBENTER@GMAIL.COM 305.781.2324

WHOIAM

Multidisciplinary UX designer passionate about making a difference, experiential technology, and cognitive psychology. Thinking across the boundaries of the digital, physical, and emotional to solve problems with holistic story and experience. I'm endlessly a curious optimist playing my part to make the future a progressively better, more empathetic, and simpler place to live.

EXPERIENCE

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER 2017-PRESENT

MICROSOFT, Redmond, WA

- Designed end-to-end for Desktop Analytics, a new product shipping January 2019 that empowers enterprise IT admins to easily adopt to Microsoft 365 by streamlining Office and Windows updates in a unified experience
- Established a piloting feature with PM and data science to overcome mundane and expensive compatibility testing of critical assets, the biggest blocker for upgrading
- Understand scope, verify needs, map user journeys, and define systems
- Collaborate with PM, research, stakeholders, and marketing to define, simplify, and iterate on story and features
- Met with engineers in an agile process to deliver prototypes from low fidelity wireframes to production quality throughout the product lifecycle
- Regulary present product for cross-company shareout and collaboration

LEAD DESIGNER & RESEARCHER 2015-2016

VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE RESEARCH GROUP, Gainesville, FL

- Created a Crisis Intervention Training VR simulation for police officers to practice de-escalation techniques for crisis situations
- Collaborated with a team of police officers, psychologists, and educators to model correct protocol, gamify, and design as a scalable system
- Mapped user journey, animated characters and environments, and spearheaded overall research and UX
- Organized a case study on the UF Police Department testing value and feasibility

DESIGNER & ANIMATOR 2015 - 2016

FREELANCE

- Co-created the first fully animated 360 music video debuted in a pop-up VR cinema for Amsterdam Dance Event
- Animated an installation for the Foot Locker store in Times Square
- Launched weekly audiovisual videos for releases on Team Tiesto
- Managed a portfolio of clients and designed vision decks and digital content

ANIMATOR 2014

VT PRODUCTION DESIGN, Los Angeles, CA

- Designed content and animated interactions for the Nike experiental marketing campaign and Santa Monica concert series installation
- Edited content for Deadmau5 and A\$AP Rocky productions

LEADERSHIP

GATOR VR FOUNDER/PRESIDENT

- Developed a community of 500+ students & teachers for cross-functional XR collaboration and development and launched a VR for good initiative
- Founded a mentorship program helping new students conduct VR/AR research with PhD students
- Coordinated biweekly meetings, social events, speakers, and workshops

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA Class of 2016 Bachelor of Arts in Digital Arts and Sciences Minor: Computer Science and Engineering Concentration: Psychology

SKILLS

User experience design Story and strategy User empathy and behavior Design research Systems design Conceptual modeling Wireframing Product definition Game design Data visualization Design thinking workshops VR design and development Animation and motion design 3D production pipeline Projection design and mapping nteractive installations 360 video Experiential marketing Audiovisual experiences Front-end development Spanish (conversational) French (conversational)

TOOLS

Sketch/Abstract/Zeplin
Figma
Adobe Creative Cloud
Microsoft Office
HTML / CSS
Maya
Unreal Engine
Unity
TouchDesigner
Arena
Madmapper